{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Garry Kasparov","incorrectAnswers":["Magnus Carlsen","Vladimir Kramnik","Bobby Fischer"],"question":"Which chess champion was beaten by a machine called Deep Blue in 1997?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Grapefruit & Tangerine ","incorrectAnswers":["Apple & Banana","Peach & Nectarine","Durian & Jackfruit"],"question":"Which two fruits are crossed to make an ugly fruit?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'The Long and Winding Road'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Principal figure of Jainism.","incorrectAnswers":["Inventor of the printing press.","Inventor of the telephone.","Queen of England from 1558 to 1603."],"question":"Which of the following was Mahavira known for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Priscilla","incorrectAnswers":["Francesca","Lisa Marie","Glady"],"question":"What was Elvis Presley's wife's name?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Vapors","incorrectAnswers":["The Proclaimers","M","Kajagoogoo"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1980 with Turning Japanese?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"(I Can't Get No) Satisfaction","incorrectAnswers":["Can't Get Used to Losing You","Killing Me Softly","Sweet Jane"],"question":"Which song, originally recorded by the Rolling Stones, was later covered by Devo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Eight","incorrectAnswers":["Four","Twelve","Sixteen"],"question":"How Many Lanes Does An Olympic Standard Swimming Pool Have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George R. R. Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Dance with Dragons'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":".html","incorrectAnswers":[".php",".js",".css"],"question":"On the Internet, what file extension is used for the content of web pages?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Egypt","incorrectAnswers":["Kuwait","Taiwan","Spain"],"question":"Cairo is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lake Ontario","incorrectAnswers":["Lake Erie","Lake Michigan","Lake Superior"],"question":"What Great Lake is located approximately 34 miles north of Lake Erie and is fed by the Niagara River?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brussels","incorrectAnswers":["Antwerp","Liège","Amsterdam"],"question":"Where city has the statue, 'Manneken Pis, depicting a naked boy urinating into a fountain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"UB40","incorrectAnswers":["Red Hot Chili Peppers","The Police","Radiohead"],"question":"What band's rendition of 'Red Red Wine' topped the charts in 1988?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1987","incorrectAnswers":["1979","1983","1991"],"question":"In which year was Full Metal Jacket released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Vodka, Orange Juice, Galliano ","incorrectAnswers":["Gin, Ginger Beer, Lemon Juice","Rum, Tequila, Tabasco Sauce, Soda","Champagne, Espresso, Mint"],"question":"What Are The Ingredients Of A Harvey Wallbanger Cocktail?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Vladimir Lenin","incorrectAnswers":["Joseph Stalin","Mikhail Gorbachev","Nikita Khrushchev"],"question":"Who was the first president of the Soviet Union?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Cape Verde is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Macbeth","incorrectAnswers":["Lear","Hamlet","Richard III"],"question":"What Shakespearean king was actually king of Scotland for 17 years?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pastel Colors","incorrectAnswers":["Neon Colors","Dark Colors","Bright Colors"],"question":"What type of color is traditionally associated with Easter?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mali","incorrectAnswers":["Belize","Bosnia and Herzegovina","Antigua and Barbuda"],"question":"Bamako is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alice Munro","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","E. T. A. Hoffmann","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Dance of the Happy Shades And Other Stories'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1955","incorrectAnswers":["1947","1963","1971"],"question":"In which year did Rosa Parks refuse to give up her seat in protest of racial inequality?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"BMW","incorrectAnswers":["Citroën","Mercedes-Benz","Honda"],"question":"Which car manufacturer makes the 3-Series?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Tennessee Williams","incorrectAnswers":["Graham Greene","Franz Grillparzer","Anthony Neilson"],"question":"What playwright wrote \"A Streetcar Named Desire\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Acat Diurna","incorrectAnswers":["Per Diem","Veni, Vidi, Vici","Memento Mori"],"question":"What was the name of the official daily notices in Ancient Rome, carved in stone and presented on message boards across the city?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Post Impressionism","incorrectAnswers":["Northern Renaissance","Washington Color School","High Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"The Flower Carrier\" by Diego Rivera is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dennis Hopper","incorrectAnswers":["Kevin Spacey","James Stewart","Robert Mitchum"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Frank Booth in Blue Velvet?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"In Our Time","incorrectAnswers":["The Moviegoer","The Baron in the Trees","Lolita"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Nick Adams'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Schiller","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Duch Německa'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Champions League","incorrectAnswers":["Roland-Garros","The ICC World Cup","The Grand National"],"question":"Which of these is a competition in soccer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Joyce","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Kurt Vonnegut","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author  wrote Ulysses, Giacomo Joyce, Dubliners and Finnegans Wake?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Iron Maiden","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Squeeze"],"question":"Which English heavy metal band released the album 'The Number of the Beast'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rome","incorrectAnswers":["Milan","Florence","Naples"],"question":"Which city in Italy is served by the Leonardo da Vinci International Airport?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Beautiful Mind","incorrectAnswers":["Gosford Park","In the Bedroom","The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2001?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Guns N' Roses","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American hard rock band released the studio album 'Chinese Democracy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Meatloaf","incorrectAnswers":["Bob Dylan","David Bowie","Marvin Gaye"],"question":"Marvin Lee Aday Is The Real Name Of Which Well Known Singer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Me and Bobby McGee","incorrectAnswers":["Angel From Montgomery","La Vie En Rose","Over the Rainbow"],"question":"Which song, originally recorded by Kris Kristofferson, was later covered by Janis Joplin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"ELO","incorrectAnswers":["The Kinks","Deep Purple","Elton John"],"question":"Who Released The 70's Album Entitled 'Out of the Blue'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Greece","incorrectAnswers":["Ireland","Austria","Portugal"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Athens?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Prague","incorrectAnswers":["Oslo","Berlin","Stockholm"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Czech Republic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Afroasiatic","Austroasiatic","Niger–Congo"],"question":"The language 'Dutch' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mark Twain","incorrectAnswers":["Cassandra Clare","Isabel Allende","George R. R. Martin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Prince and the Pauper'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edgar Rice Burroughs","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Vance","George R. R. Martin","Robert A. Heinlein"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Tarzan'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Friends","incorrectAnswers":["Seinfeld","The Simpsons","Frasier"],"question":"Which popular '90s sitcom featured the character of Rachel Green?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Coventry","incorrectAnswers":["Birmingham","Nottingham","Sheffield"],"question":"Through the streets of what town did Lady Godiva ride naked?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Squire","incorrectAnswers":["Tourney","Knight errant","Groom"],"question":"What was the name given to a knight's student?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Paris ","incorrectAnswers":["Madrid","Rome","Brussels"],"question":"Where is Le Figaro published?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bhutan","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Nepal","Myanmar"],"question":"____________ is derived from the Indian word Bhotanta, meaning \"the edge of Tibet.\" It is located in Asia near the southern fringes of the eastern Himalayas.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'I Want to Hold Your Hand'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brazzaville","incorrectAnswers":["Conakry","Dakar","Nairobi"],"question":"What is the capital of Congo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A fish","incorrectAnswers":[" A lion","A cow","An octopus"],"question":"In the biblical story, what does Jonah get swallowed by?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chicago","incorrectAnswers":["Vancouver","St. Petersberg","Sao Paolo"],"question":"Which city is known as the Windy City?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Red Hot Chili Peppers","incorrectAnswers":["The Monkees","Black Flag","Journey"],"question":"Which band is John Frusciante a part of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Hagia Sophia","incorrectAnswers":["Topkapi Palace","Blue Mosque","Ephesus"],"question":"Which famous Turkish landmark started as a Byzantine Christian cathedral, then was converted to an Ottoman imperial mosque, became a museum, and in 2020 became a Mosque again?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Talk to you later","incorrectAnswers":["The two year lapse","Try to yeet loads","Top thanks you legend"],"question":"If someone typed the letters 'TTYL' in a message, what would they mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venezuela","incorrectAnswers":["Canada","Zimbabwe","Australia"],"question":"Where is Angel Falls?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Leo Tolstoy","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Resurrection'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Reptiles","incorrectAnswers":["Mammals","Amphibians","Lizards"],"question":"Marine iguanas, saltwater crocodiles, sea snakes, and sea turtles are the only surviving seawater __________","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Twisted Sister","incorrectAnswers":["Men Without Hats","Brownsville Station","Spandau Ballet"],"question":"'We're Not Gonna Take It' was a one hit wonder in 1984 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Seven Years' War","incorrectAnswers":["The Hundred Years' War","The War of the Spanish Succession","The Napoleonic Wars"],"question":"What was the name of the major conflict between France, Austria, Prussia, Saxony, Russia and Great Britain in the 18th century?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Black Forest","incorrectAnswers":["Blue Mountains","Emerald Valley","Yellow River"],"question":"What German region is renowned for its spas and cuckoo clocks?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Portugal","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","Czechia","Liberia"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Two vertical bands of green  and red with the national coat of arms towards the left.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It was reusable","incorrectAnswers":["It had no rocket engines","It didn't enter outer space","It didn't use fuel"],"question":"What made the space shuttle different from previous orbital spacecraft?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jefferson","incorrectAnswers":["Washington","Lincoln","Franklin"],"question":"Which president was responsible for the Louisiana Purchase?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Veneto","incorrectAnswers":["Tuscany","Piedmont","Sicily"],"question":"What region of Italy is home to Amarone and Valpolicella wines?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Uniform","incorrectAnswers":["Unable","Underneath","Umbrella"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter U?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry VIII","incorrectAnswers":["Edward IV","Edward I","George IV"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1509-1547?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lactose","incorrectAnswers":["Fructose","Maltose","Saccharin"],"question":"Which sugar is found in milk?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Janis Joplin","incorrectAnswers":["Jimi Hendrix","Bob Marley","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Whose Debut Solo Album Was \"I Got Dem Kosmic Blues Again Mama\" In 1969?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Family over everything","incorrectAnswers":["To each his own","Familiarity breeds contempt","Farming is the backbone"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Familia supra omnia' translate into English?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Chests","incorrectAnswers":["Wardrobes","Chairs","Tables"],"question":"Used by brides in the past to collect their belongings before marriage, bridal, dower, and hope are all types of what piece of furniture?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Air conditioning","incorrectAnswers":["Asbestos control","Allergen correction","Audio capabilities"],"question":"In HVAC what do the letters AC stand for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Joshua","incorrectAnswers":["Daniel","Solomon","David"],"question":"Who replaced Moses as the prophet of the Israelites?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Silent Night","incorrectAnswers":["The Holly and the Ivy","Oh, Holy Night","We Three Kings"],"question":"What is the English title of the Christmas carol written by the Austrian Josef Mohr, originally called 'Stille Nacht'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belgrade","incorrectAnswers":["Lyon","Geneva","Milan"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Serbia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Old Curiosity Shop","incorrectAnswers":["Oliver Twist","David Copperfield","Great Expectations"],"question":"Which Charles Dickens novel begins with the line 'Night is generally my time for walking'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bioluminescent","incorrectAnswers":["Glogasmic","Technicolor","Natulight"],"question":"Animals and plants which produce light are said to be what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cambodia","incorrectAnswers":["Netherlands","Lebanon","Bhutan"],"question":"Phnom Penh is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Oscar De La Hoya","incorrectAnswers":["Floyd Mayweather Jr.","Muhammad Ali","Mike Tyson"],"question":"Who was known as boxing's 'Golden Boy' and now promotes a stable of fighters under his Golden Boy Promotions?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cheers & Frasier","incorrectAnswers":["Seinfeld & Friends","The Big Bang Theory & How I Met Your Mother","The Office & Brooklyn Nine-Nine"],"question":"On which two popular sitcoms has Bebe Neuwirth played Dr. Lilith Sternin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lady of Shalott","incorrectAnswers":["Lady Macbeth","Lady Godiva","Lady Elizabeth"],"question":"Which Lady is imprisoned in a castle near Camelot in a Tennyson poem?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sweet ","incorrectAnswers":["Dry","Light","Crisp"],"question":"What Does Demi Sec Mean On A Champagne Bottle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Slovenia","Hungary","Croatia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Czech Republic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Baby Pac-Man","incorrectAnswers":["Miss Pac-Man","Mrs Pac-Man","Super Pac-Man"],"question":"What was the hybrid pinball/video game in the Pac-Man series?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eagle","incorrectAnswers":["Elephant","Bat","Bull"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the American Airlines logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"I love you","incorrectAnswers":["Good morning","Thank you","Excuse me"],"question":"What does the Spanish 'Te amo' mean in English?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Sino-Tibetan","Niger–Congo","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Moroccan Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Toni Basil","incorrectAnswers":["Wild Cherry","Edwyn Collins","Terry Jacks"],"question":"'Mickey' was a one hit wonder in 1982 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iceland","incorrectAnswers":["Czechia","Switzerland","Angola"],"question":"Reykjavik is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Zurich","incorrectAnswers":["Bern","Geneva","Basel"],"question":"What is Switzerland's most populous city?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Neptune","incorrectAnswers":["Uranus","Saturn","Jupiter"],"question":"Which is the outermost planet in the Solar System?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Paranoid","incorrectAnswers":["Psycho","Crazy","Insane"],"question":"Name Black Sabbath's debut hit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A herd","incorrectAnswers":["A brood","A watch","A plump"],"question":"What is the word for a group of buffaloes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nepal","incorrectAnswers":["Sri Lanka","Bangladesh","Pakistan"],"question":"Which country is surrounded by India on three sides and China to the north?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Colorado","incorrectAnswers":["Mississippi","Amazon","Hudson"],"question":"What major river cuts through the Grand Canyon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"David Yates","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 1?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Carlsberg ","incorrectAnswers":["Heineken","Fosters","Stella Artois"],"question":"What beer was promoted with the line: 'Probably the best lager in the world'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"McDonald's ","incorrectAnswers":["KFC","Burger King","Wendy's"],"question":"What fast food chain was taken over by Ray Kroc in 1954?","difficulty":"medium"},